A Guide to the Alice M. Reilly papers, 1925-1968
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Alice M. Reilly papers, 1925-1968
The Library of Virginia
51831
1.35 cubic feet and 3 boxes
Alice M. Reilly
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Purchased.
Biographical Information
Alice Marie Reilly was born 31 May 1911 in Nassau County, New York, to John Vincent Reilly (1878-1960) and Bertha Margaret Heuschkel Reilly (1885-1977). The family moved to Albemarle County, Virginia, about the time the Second World War began. Alice Reilly served as a nurse's aide at the Ashford General Hospital in Warm Springs, West Virginia. The hospital was a military hospital caring for wounded soldiers. After the war ended, the Reillys moved to Ashland, Virginia. Alice Reilly died in Ashland 12 June 2002, and was buried in Woodland Cemetery in Ashland.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1925-1968, of Alice M. Reilly of Albemarle County and Ashland, Virginia, consisting of correspondence, 1944, from Alice Reilly (1911-2002), White Sulphur Springs, West Virginia, to John Vincent Reilly (1878-1960) and Bertha M. Heuschkel Reilly (1885-1977), Albemarle County, Virginia, detailing her life and work as a nurse's aide at Ashford General Hospital, a military hospital located in Greenbrier County, West Virginia. Includes a letter, 25-27 June 1968, from Mary Jane McLean to Alice and Bertha Reilly describing her life in Malaga, Spain; as well as Christmas cards. Collection also contains photographs of the Reillys, family friends, horses, dogs, vacation sites, and homes, including Albemarle County, Ashland, and Richmond, Virginia; vacation trips to New Jersey, New York, Pennsylvania, Nova Scotia, and Puerto Rico. Collection includes negatives of photographs and an empty matchbook from the Island Inn at Hobe Sound, Florida.
Contents List
- Letters, March 1944. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Letters, April 1944. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Letters, May 1944. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Letters, June 1944. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Letters, July 1944. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Letters, August 1944. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Letters, September 1944. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Letters, October [and November?] 1944. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Envelope, 21 October 1944. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Letter, 25-27 June 1944. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Christmas cards, no date. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Photographs--Alice Reilly (solo). (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Photographs--Alice Reilly (with parents and friends). (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Photographs--Alice Reilly (with animals). (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Photographs--John V. Reilly and Bertha Reilly (some with friends). (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Photographs--John V. Reilly and Bertha Reilly (for related photos see Box 2, Folder 9). (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Photographs--Jody Hartnedy, John Hartnedy (father and son), and Porter Davis. (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Photographs--Peg and Harry Thielman's wedding. (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Photographs--Betty Young and Mary Howe (sisters). (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Photographs--Emily P. Lacy. (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Photographs--Nancy and Huckleberry Finn. (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Photographs--women (identified). (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Photographs--men (identified). (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Photographs--men and women (identified). (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Photographs--children (identified). (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Photographs--women (individual, unidentified). (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Photographs--women (groups of 2 or more, unidentified). (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Photographs--men (unidentified). (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Photographs--men and women (groups, unidentified). (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Photographs--adults and children (unidentified). (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Photographs--children (unidentified). (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Photographs--horses (for related photos, see Box 1, Folder 16). (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Photographs--horses. (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Photographs--dogs. (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Photographs--blessing of hounds. (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Photographs--Florida. (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Photographs--Atlantic City, 1948. (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Photographs--Central Park. (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Photographs--Criglersville (Madison County, Virginia). (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Photographs--Jamestown. (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Photographs--Keswick Park (Albemarle County, Virginia). (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Photographs--Long Beach (New York) after a hurricane. (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Photographs--Mayhurst (Orange County, Virginia). (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Photographs--Mount Pocono (Pennsylvania). (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Photographs--616 Park Street (Charlottesville, Virginia). (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Photographs--Puerto Rico, 1937. (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Photographs--Reid Avenue (Rockville Center, New York), 1938, 1942. (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Photographs--Richmond, 26 December 1925. (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Photographs--Rockville (Front Royal, Virginia). (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Photographs--Schooley's Mountain (New Jersey). (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Photographs--Springdale (Albemarle County, Virginia?). (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Photographs--Stratford Hall (Westmoreland County, Virginia). (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Photographs--University of Virginia. (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Photographs--near West Haven (Connecticut). (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Photographs--Daffodils. (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Photographs--Blackman Photo Service, 1932. (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Photographs--Blackman Photo Service, 1933. (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Photographs--Blackman Photo Service, 1940. (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Photographs--July 1952. (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Photographs--Kodacolor, 1954-1955, 1957. (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Photographs--1956. (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Photographs--1957. (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Photographs--1958. (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Photographs--July 1967. (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Photographs--G. L. Hall Optical Co. Photo Dept. (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Photographs--locations in Virginia (identified). (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Photographs--buildings and locations (identified). (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Photographs--buildings and locations (unidentified). (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Photographs--parade (unidentified location). (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Photograph albums--Tammy and Hoagie (dogs), 1961. (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Photograph albums--Nova Scotia vacation, 1954. (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Photograph albums--unidentified location. (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Negatives--the Hartnedys. (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Negatives--Hurricane Connie, 1955. (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Negatives--from envelope addressed to Mrs. John V. Reilly from Belle M. Reilly, 1964. (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Negatives--Posto Photo Service. (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Negatives--Stanbi Photo Service, envelope marked Va. Neg. (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Negatives--Stanbi Photo Service, envelope marked Virginia. (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Negatives--Stanbi Photo Service. (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Negatives--Kodacolor envelope. (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Negatives--Kodacolor envelope. (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Negatives--Kodak Verichrome. (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Negatives--Kodak Verichrome. (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Negatives--Kodak Verichrome. (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Negatives--from Miller and Rhoads envelope. (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Negatives--from monthly collection evelope. (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Negatives--envelope marked negatives, but empty. (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Matchbook cover from Island Inn, Hobe Sound, Florida. (Box 3, Folder 34)